Hi, in this lesson, even with all how to make numbers in your calculator easier to read by adding
thousand separators. But not just adding with the I like with some custom logic, we should
don't understand because it's written complex, it uses a lot of regular expressions, a lot of
searching and etc. So it's a really custom way. So we'll replace it on sums in much easier.
So, in this lesson, we will be researching the JavaScript libraries that can handle
number formatting. Look always to understand what those exist, how they differ and what features
they offer. Like localization, custom separators, decimal formatting, etc. We will use
AI to do a research right here in the query chat. And you'll also take a look at the
pros and cons of each option and see some simple examples of what comparison. And next, we
will refactor the number formatting using this library. We will refactor this function to use
a library approach and to have ever seen as we want to look at same like this. So by
the end of this lesson, you will know how to format numbers consistently using a JavaScript
libraries and how to do a quick research using AI in a hard compiler. So I suggest, let's get started.
I will use Ask mode for doing the research because I don't need to apply any changes, so please
also switch it. And I have problem. I will ask search for JavaScript libraries that can
format numbers with thousand separators. Compare some popular options and summarize pros,
cons and short code example for each. Now let's start and let's see what research it will do.
I will increase the chat window size. So we have the numero.js, okay, it's have the full number
formatting etc. It also shows how many stars it has on GitHub and how much what is the size of the
library? We have Intel number format. So the first one looks really simple. Just say the format.
The next one, more dependencies native browser support and their bundle size.
All I think I like this one because it's built in, we shouldn't install anything. So JavaScript
and browser already supported. How it's used? We can use it Intel number format, provide the location
provide grouping and maximum digit fraction digits. A grouping separator, okay, it's good that
we can provide a grouping separator. So I like it. The next one is format.js. It's a larger bundle
size. So you see it also looks same as number format, but it just a separate library. Okay.
And the recommendation for this calculator project use the Intel number format. So AI give us
the recommendation because it's already built in in browsers. It's their bundle size. It's simple
to customize separator and more external dependencies. So when you can use, you can replace the
current formatting with this example. But the maximum fraction digits is not okay for us because
but I think it's fine because we will control it. Oh, let's start. So you can just ask, okay,
just implement it or you can click it apply to source utils format number.
And if you replace all the code, let's click heap. I will reduce the size. Now we see that grouping
separator doesn't exist. Okay, now I will ask AI fix it because sometimes it can
respond to the sums and doesn't really exist. So I will copy paste this error and we'll say to AI,
but I will use the agent mode now that he love fix it. So it looks simple. We check if there is no
value of your return zero, if value is equal, the dash will return value to interesting.
Then we parse a number and then we try to format it.
Okay, so we will keep the code and I will explain to you. So there is small ability to provide
a group separator because the image will use his own separator as a comma as we see and we just
will replace it on space. So let's check how it works, but it looks much more simpler. So either
a fresh page, I will start typing numbers. We see the silent format and it works.
I'll let me check how the decimal, the decimal is also works. It might be
so let's let's multiply it and click equal. Yeah, we see everything works fine.
I like it. I guess you do. So if you see any complex code, you can ask AI to use some library,
you can do first research and then ask to apply it. So for example, this logic is really simple,
the calculate logic also simple, you can also ask to refactor your quality for like.
Okay, I hope this lesson was useful for you. And now you know about this
last library is that you can use it for formatting and see you in the next lessons.